<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>circuit bending - altLab - DIT Creativity</title>
	<atom:link href="https://altlab.org/tag/circuit-bending/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://altlab.org</link>
	<description>Lisbon&#039;s [DIT] Do It Together Hackerspace</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 22:20:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.6</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Workshop Ruído Táctil</title>
		<link>https://altlab.org/2011/04/05/workshop-ruido-tactil/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 22:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[circuit bending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[synthesizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workshop]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://altlab.org/?p=1751</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Neste workshop, com a duração de 2 dias, iremos construir sintetizadores low-tech, reactivos ao toque, capazes de produzir uma variedade de sons e texturas em função da posição, humidade e pressão dos dedos que tocarem em pontos-de-contacto destes instrumentos. As tarefas nas quais os participantes vão ser envolvidos permitir-lhes-ão familiarizarem-se com os princípios básicos da &#8230; <a href="https://altlab.org/2011/04/05/workshop-ruido-tactil/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Workshop Ruído Táctil"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top">Neste workshop, com a duração de 2 dias, iremos construir sintetizadores <em>low-tech</em>, reactivos ao toque, capazes de produzir uma variedade de sons e texturas em função da posição, humidade e pressão dos dedos que tocarem em pontos-de-contacto destes instrumentos.
<p><img decoding="async" src="http://audienciazero.org/images/stories/2011/workshops/wk_ruido_tactil_23_04_2011.jpg" alt></p>
<p>As tarefas nas quais os participantes vão ser envolvidos permitir-lhes-ão familiarizarem-se com os princípios básicos da electrónica, nomeadamente componentes, esquemas electrónicos e processo de soldagem. Não se exige experiência prévia como pré-requisito e o workshop é destinado a todos os curiosos com mais de 15 anos.</p>
<p>Cada participante terminará o workshop com um sintetizador construído por si, que permitirá acabar com o sossego de co-habitantes, humanos, caninos ou felinos.</p>
<p>Pede-se que os participantes tragam consigo objectos de madeira, plástico ou cartão, que possam ser furados (caixas, tupperwares, frascos, etc) nos quais pretendam alojar o seu sintetizador.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><br>
Workshop Ruído Táctil</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Formador: André Castro<br>
Coordenador: Tiago Serra<br>
Datas: 23 e 24 de Abril de 2011<br>
Horário: 10h30-13h00 // 14h30-18h00<br>
Local: xDA — Rua Aires de Campos, 6 (Coimbra)<br>
Preço: 30 euros</p>
<p>Estado:</p>
<p>Abertas as Inscrições</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://audienciazero.org/index.php?option=com_cct&amp;task=inforequest&amp;id=173">Pedido de Informações</a></p>
<p><a href="http://audienciazero.org/index.php?option=com_cct&amp;task=workshops&amp;id=173">Ficha de Inscrição</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><strong>Em breve em Lisboa também, no altLab é claro <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><br>
</strong><strong>Stay Tuned!</strong></h3>
<p>&nbsp;</p></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Arduino Hack Day</title>
		<link>https://altlab.org/2011/01/24/arduino-hack-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 17:22:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arduino]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[circuit bending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hacklab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prototype]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workshop]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://altlab.org/?p=1391</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I want to join !]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2><a href="http://altlab.org/events/#AHD">I want to join !</a></h2>
<p><a href="http://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/FLYER_Arduino-Hack-Day_web.jpg"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1392" title="FLYER_Arduino-Hack-Day_web" src="http://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/FLYER_Arduino-Hack-Day_web.jpg" alt width="600" height="851"></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>a glove that lights up when you shake hands</title>
		<link>https://altlab.org/2010/03/03/a-glove-that-lights-up-when-you-shake-hands/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catarina M.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 19:55:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[circuit bending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[materials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prototype]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[soft circuits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tutorial]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://altlab.org/?p=667</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This mitten lights up when its wearer shakes hands with someone. It has two exposed soft contacts around the thumb and across the palm which, when bridged by bare skin, turn on the LED embedded on the flower. The mitten itself was created by fashion designer Isabel Tomás, and we then sewed a simple touch &#8230; <a href="https://altlab.org/2010/03/03/a-glove-that-lights-up-when-you-shake-hands/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "a glove that lights up when you shake hands"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="http://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/mitten_00.jpg" alt="light up glove" title="light up glove" width="500" height="375" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-671"></p>
<p>This mitten lights up when its wearer shakes hands with someone. It has two exposed soft contacts around the thumb and across the palm which, when bridged by bare skin, turn on the LED embedded on the flower. The mitten itself was created by fashion designer <a href="http://amoresdetoquio.blogspot.com/">Isabel Tomás</a>, and we then sewed a simple touch switch circuit onto it using conductive fabric and thread. It also works with high fives and holding hands <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="http://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/double.jpg" alt="high five and holding hands" title="high five and holding hands" width="500" height="188" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-672"></p>
<p><object width="400" height="300"><param name="allowfullscreen" value="true"><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"><param name="movie" value="http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=9851076&amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;show_title=1&amp;show_byline=1&amp;show_portrait=0&amp;color=&amp;fullscreen=1"><embed src="http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=9851076&amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;show_title=1&amp;show_byline=1&amp;show_portrait=0&amp;color=&amp;fullscreen=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" width="400" height="300"></object></p>
<p>Isabel and I designed this as a soft circuits exercise for some upcoming materials workshops. You can find all the instructions and images we prepared for this purpose @ openMaterials:<br>
http://openmaterials.org/2010/03/03/making-a-glove-that-lights-up-with-a-hand-shake/</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>First Soft Circuits Open Lab</title>
		<link>https://altlab.org/2010/02/19/first-soft-circuits-open-lab/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catarina M.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 12:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altLab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[circuit bending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[materials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repurpose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[soft circuits]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://altlab.org/?p=600</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This Sunday we’re holding our first Soft Circuits Open Lab at the School of Fine Arts in Lisbon (FBAUL — Faculdade de Belas Artes de Lisboa). There is no predefined structure for the event. We will meet for the course of one day with the purposes of sharing knowledge, experimenting freely, advancing on-going projects, and &#8230; <a href="https://altlab.org/2010/02/19/first-soft-circuits-open-lab/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "First Soft Circuits Open Lab"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="http://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/softcircuitsAltlab.jpg" alt="soft circuits open lab" title="soft circuits open lab" width="500" height="375" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-655"></p>
<p>This Sunday we’re holding our first Soft Circuits Open Lab at the School of Fine Arts in Lisbon <a href="http://www.fba.ul.pt/portal/page?_pageid=401,1&amp;_dad=portal&amp;_schema=PORTAL" target="_blank">(FBAUL — Faculdade de Belas Artes de Lisboa)</a>. There is no predefined structure for the event. We will meet for the course of one day with the purposes of sharing knowledge, experimenting freely, advancing on-going projects, and just having fun working together. Some of the people attending will be specialists in electronics and others in textiles. Barcamp style impromptu presentations are very welcome.</p>
<p>Altlab will provide some basic tools such as pliers, scissors, soldering irons, ironing board, etc. But participants must bring all the materials and additional equipment necessary for their own projects/experiments (including laptops). Here are some suggestions: any kind of fabric, needles and thread, yarn, t‑shirts, conductive and/or resistive fabric, conductive thread, conductive and/or resistive yarn, knitting and/or crochet needles, LEDs, coin cell batteries, battery holders, EL wire, strands of fiber optics, copper foil, copper adhesive track, aluminum foil, resistive foam, regular foam, arduinos (lilypad or any other kind). If you’ve never worked with any of these materials and don’t have them handy, come anyway, you can help someone else with their project and learn along the way.</p>
<p>For more information on soft circuits techniques and materials, check out the <a href="http://openmaterials.org/wiki/index.php?title=Main_Page#Soft_Circuits_Resources" target="_blank">Soft Circuits Resources</a> section on the <a href="http://openmaterials.org" target="_blank">openMaterials</a> wiki.</p>
<p>This open lab will take place on February 21st, from 10:30 to 18:30, at the School of Fine Arts in Lisbon, room 307, 1st floor (since our own space is still under construction). All are welcome, there is no fee nor registration, but please do let me know if you are planning on coming: catarinamota(at)audienciazero.org</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Drum Pads</title>
		<link>https://altlab.org/2009/08/04/drum-pads/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ricardo Webbens]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2009 17:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[circuit bending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drum pads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[materials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recycle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://altlablx.org/?p=489</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hey. Four drum pads ready to go. All made of old material found in the Alt/Lab installations, and a very special big thankxxx for Mónica who brought the casings (we are going back to that in a moment) for the drum pads. So the idea was to make drum pads that we could hook up &#8230; <a href="https://altlab.org/2009/08/04/drum-pads/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Drum Pads"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="320" height="240" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-490" src="http://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2009/08/drumpads1.jpg" alt="drumpads1"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-491" src="http://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2009/08/drumpads2.jpg" alt="drumpads2" width="320" height="240"></p>
<p>Hey.</p>
<p>Four drum pads ready to go.</p>
<p>All made of old material found in the Alt/Lab installations, and a very special big thankxxx for Mónica who brought the casings (we are going back to that in a moment) for the drum pads.</p>
<p>So the idea was to make drum pads that we could hook up to a sound card(or whatever) and them make sweet music, this is a very nice combination between piezoelectric components and a few layers of some absorbent sound&nbsp; material like rubber or cork foil (that’s what we use because there was nothing more) and a piece of aluminum foil for a greater drum area .</p>
<p>We use an old can (20l) of paint, four piezoelectric found in electronic junk like old modems and old telephones, wire for connecting the piezos, cork foil for insulation the drum pad area and Mónica supply the casings (square rubber cd´s stands), and glue for putting everything nice and tight .</p>
<p>First we cut a piece of the can (circular about 10cm radius)and we glued the piezo into it, then we drilled one hole into the rubber casing for the wires to came out, them we cut two square cork foil parts (the first in the bottom of the casing and the other for the top) a bit of glue and that’s it drum pads ready to rock.</p>
<p>Now we got some audio coming out of the pads but thats just boring because its always the same and we want to go further like transforming audio into midi messages, and we found the right tool for it, its called&nbsp; “<a href="http://koen.smartelectronix.com/KTDrumTrigger/" target="_blank">KTDrumTrigger</a>” and he transforms the audio signal into midi notes, we can use this midi notes inside a sequencer program to control any kind of instrument (either VSTI or some other stuff), in our case we use the drum pads to control “<a href="http://www.native-instruments.com/#/en/products/producer/battery-3/" target="_blank">Battery</a>” and thats it instant fun.</p>
<p>There are some other links and some other ideas for drum pads. This “<a href="http://www.spikenzielabs.com/SpikenzieLabs/DrumKitKit.html">one</a>“uses ardunio as a source for the imput signal.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="320" height="240" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-494" src="http://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2009/08/drumpads3.jpg" alt="drumpads3"></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Circuit Bending</title>
		<link>https://altlab.org/2009/05/08/circuit-bending/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ricardo Webbens]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2009 23:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[circuit bending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reed ghazala]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[savant syndrome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[synthesizer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://altlablx.org/?p=281</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello “intrenets” people(s) This post today reflects a little about&#160; what circuit bending and diy are. I have many friends and colleagues&#160; asking me “-So what is circuit bending?”, well here goes the awser and a bit of the history behind circuit bending. Seems that a guy called Reed Ghazala, was making experiments with some &#8230; <a href="https://altlab.org/2009/05/08/circuit-bending/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Circuit Bending"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="alignleft" src="http://casperelectronics.com/images/finishedpieces/speak-n-spell/LaDicteeSupreme/S3600036.JPG" alt width="199" height="262"></p>
<p>Hello “intrenets” people(s)</p>
<p>This post today reflects a little about&nbsp; what circuit bending and diy are.</p>
<p>I have many friends and colleagues&nbsp; asking me “-So what is circuit bending?”, well here goes the awser and a bit of the history behind circuit bending.</p>
<p>Seems that a guy called Reed Ghazala, was making experiments with some synthesizers, trying to get some more sounds out of the electronic instruments, so he decided to open one and poke the guts of the beast .</p>
<p>He soon&nbsp; finds out that the core of an electronic instrument its a lot of fun and this could be exciting discover.</p>
<p>Now…have you ever heard of the Savant syndrome ?&nbsp; a person who as Savant Syndrome have the ability of mixing emotions, like seeing numbers in a wide variety of colors or the alphabet in shapes and forms, the cause of this, its simply the brain and some short fuses in some areas, and this its exactly what Circuit bending is.</p>
<p>So, when Reed decided to explore the possibility of the short circuit he open a big door for experimental music and a new form of seeing electronic devices, the idea its simply brilliant, lets open some toys, synths, pedals (whatever) and lets start to take some really cool sounds out of it, and the brilliant part is : you don’t need to know about electronics or be a geek who spent all day in the garage (myself included), because circuit bending its like a a brain in short fuse.</p>
<p>What you need to circuit bending some stuff ?&nbsp; This is another question and an important one. Hummm lets see:</p>
<p>First, you will need some kind of device that produces sound, like a toy, a distortion pedal, an old synth just to name a few.</p>
<p>Second, this is the important part DON’T USE ANYTHING THAT CONNECTS DIRECTLY TO THE AC/DC POWER, this means DEATH, instead use batteries, all kinds of batteries and even transformers as long you don’t touch that evil 220 V you are in business .</p>
<p>Third, open your device and choose your method of operation, this could be done in a variety of ways, you could use your fingers with a little of saliva (ughhh), or two screw drivers connected by an alligator clip.</p>
<p>Four, explore and see if the device reacts to your touch poking some circuits, i often get some great results poking the chips legs and connecting them together, finding the cool points its fun so don’t give up if you don’t find something in the first 5 minutes.</p>
<p>Five, ohh the “intrenets” yes there’s a lot in here just search a bit and you will find yourself in a brand new world, of course the circuit bending community its open minded and friendly, so don’t be shy and ask questions (most of us don’t know what are doing so join the club).</p>
<p>Now you know were Beck, Madonna, Mike Patton and many others are getting they inspiration (yeah that’s right Madonna), the musical possibility are immense, just think&nbsp; is you, who&nbsp; are discovering your own sounds and making it at the same time (not like a patch in a synthesizer ) something really new and fresh made entirely&nbsp; by you.</p>
<p>So,&nbsp; what is Circuit Bending&nbsp; ?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
