<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>residency - altLab - DIT Creativity</title>
	<atom:link href="https://altlab.org/tag/residency/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://altlab.org</link>
	<description>Lisbon&#039;s [DIT] Do It Together Hackerspace</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 09:28:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.6</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Creative Politics Artistic Residency</title>
		<link>https://altlab.org/2012/10/15/creative-politics-artistic-residency/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 21:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[residency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://altlab.org/?p=3807</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Posted on&#160;xDA&#160;Blog&#160;by&#160;Filipe&#160;Cruz Some members of the AZ Labs community have been gathering in artistic residency in Guimarães once more, the topic for this residency is Creative Politics, meaning to come up ideas and projects connecting the citizens back with the political system. Complaining is easy, presenting solutions is harder. Citizens feel disconnected with politics and &#8230; <a href="https://altlab.org/2012/10/15/creative-politics-artistic-residency/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Creative Politics Artistic Residency"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Posted on&nbsp;<time datetime="2012-10-11T11:16:29+00:00" pubdate><span class="GRspelling"><a title="11:16 am" href="http://audienciazero.net/xda/2012/10/11/creative-politics-artistic-residency/" rel="bookmark">x</a>DA</span>&nbsp;Blog</time>&nbsp;by&nbsp;<a title="View all posts by ps" href="http://audienciazero.net/xda/author/filipecruz/" rel="author">Filipe&nbsp;Cruz</a></p>
<div>
<p>Some members of the AZ Labs community have been gathering in <span id="GRmark_74d4d8cd7aec6bc0abc3a8e7edc7ff38fd8688dd_artistic residency:0" class="GRcorrect">artistic residency</span> in Guimarães once more, the topic for this residency is Creative Politics, meaning to come up ideas and projects connecting the citizens back <span id="GRmark_74d4d8cd7aec6bc0abc3a8e7edc7ff38fd8688dd_with:1" class="GRcorrect">with</span> the political system. Complaining is easy, presenting solutions is harder. Citizens feel disconnected with politics and disengage themselves from these issues. We are trying to counter that with artistic or otherwise useful projects and proposals.</p>
<p>During the first weekend we <span id="GRmark_2afa17bd89d03a61d12db3b09cc354ff43e5bda8_had running:0" class="GRcorrect">had running</span> at LCD a parallel event named Antropocode, part of the&nbsp;<a href="http://atlanticarc.net/">Atlantic Arc Summer of Labs 2012</a>. During the weekend over a dozen artists and hackers from Portugal and Spain were gathered developing concepts and projects in a <span id="GRmark_71f9bb24cb0f3a52fc43893ff3641238ea29de41_hackaton:0" class="GRcorrect">hackaton</span> about the borderline of body and technology. Some of the projects were also related to the creative politics theme.</p>
<p>The <span id="GRmark_9f1bbb1c8a5f66f2fd137d27bc2cfc115fa52490_hackaton:0" class="GRcorrect">hackaton</span> is now over but the Creative Politics artistic residency continues with a dozen other folks, mostly folks from Portugal but also including some foreigners. The first days have been focused on brainstorming project ideas. You can find more information&nbsp;<a href="http://audienciazero.net/docs/public/events/creative-politics-2012/">on our wiki</a>.</p>
<p>Some examples of projects currently being developed:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reclaiming Data</strong><br>
Research and&nbsp;<a href="http://opendata-pt.blogspot.pt/">documentation</a>&nbsp;of open data initiatives in Portugal, the end goal is to develop a viral video calling for more active participation and involvement from the citizens or a <span id="GRmark_29aca6790f1c8b720aef0a82607d86ac21a6279d_webtool:0" class="GRcorrect">webtool</span> to request missing data.</li>
<li><strong>Hacking Urban Resources</strong><br>
Research and&nbsp;<a href="http://audienciazero.net/docs/public/events/creative-politics-2012/hacking-urban-resources">documentation</a>&nbsp;of ways to hack urban resources to improve the way of life at a local level in Guimarães, bringing back the control of the city to the citizens. A sample book on how to re-appropriate, re-use local resources and also on how to re-learn useful old skills.</li>
<li><strong>Political Manager</strong><br>
A web based game where you play the role of a rising politician and have to improve your skills to build your career without succumbing to the pressures of the dark side.</li>
<li><strong>Comparative News</strong><br>
The goal of this project is to help citizens understand the trends and tendencies in the political discourse that the media present to them <span id="GRmark_5c2cf69ab8f8b09804500f4f757dbfb166157f67_everyday:0" class="GRcorrect">everyday</span>. The strategy is to compare different sources of information, like newspapers, radio and television using data visualization. The intuition behind this project is that comparing sources enable people to see the big picture, to identify what’s important and what’s not.</li>
</ul>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>TANGÍVEIS — Residência AZ 2012</title>
		<link>https://altlab.org/2011/11/28/residencia-az-2012/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 10:08:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altLab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arduino]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[residency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workshop]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://altlab.org/?p=2792</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; A Audiência Zero vai realizar mais uma residência artística multidisciplinar em O Espaço do Tempo (Montemor-o-Novo), entre os dias 14 a 22 de Janeiro. Nesta edição, teremos uma novidade 🙂 Enquanto nas edições anteriores os participantes eram convidados a desenvolver qualquer tipo de projecto, individual ou colectivamente, nas áreas de electrónica, computação física, instalações &#8230; <a href="https://altlab.org/2011/11/28/residencia-az-2012/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "TANGÍVEIS — Residência AZ 2012"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>A Audiência Zero vai realizar mais uma residência artística multidisciplinar em <a href="http://www.oespacodotempo.pt/" target="_blank">O Espaço do Tempo (Montemor-o-Novo)</a>, entre os dias 14 a 22 de Janeiro.</p>
<p>Nesta edição, teremos uma novidade <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Enquanto nas edições anteriores os participantes eram convidados a desenvolver qualquer tipo de projecto, individual ou colectivamente, nas áreas de electrónica, computação física, instalações interactivas, etc., este ano propomos também um objectivo comum: o desenvolvimento de interacções tangíveis, através da construção de objectos e espaços interactivos capazes de demonstrar que um objecto pode causar interacções distintas em espaços distintos. A ideia é fazer com que cada objecto a desenvolver interaja de forma diferenciada nos espaços criados, ou que os objectos interajam entre eles próprios.</p>
<p>Deixamos aqui alguns exemplos de ideias a abordar.</p>
<p>Imagine um objecto a ser levado para determinado espaço onde está uma luz robotizada. Quando o objecto é “reconhecido” no espaço, a luz robotizada passa a seguir a pessoa que o carrega. Se o objecto for dado a outra pessoa, passa então ela a ser seguida pela luz.</p>
<p>
<a href="https://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/followspots.jpg"><img width="150" height="137" src="https://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/followspots.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt decoding="async" loading="lazy"></a>
<a href="https://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/augmentedhopscotch.jpg"><img width="150" height="134" src="https://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/augmentedhopscotch.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt decoding="async" loading="lazy"></a>
<a href="https://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/balloons.jpg"><img width="150" height="119" src="https://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/balloons.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt decoding="async" loading="lazy"></a>
<br>
É possível desenvolver outras interacções semelhantes, por exemplo:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ao apontar os objectos uns para os outros, os objectos reagem com som, luzes, etc.;</li>
<li>Ao alterar a sua posição no espaço, o objecto reage com som, luzes, etc.;</li>
<li>Ao alterar a sua posição no espaço, o objecto faz com que o espaço reaja com projecções de vídeo, som, luzes, etc.;</li>
<li>A mesma posição no espaço pode causar interacções diferentes com cada um dos objectos.</li>
</ul>
<p>Podem ser desenvolvidas diversas narrativas – artísticas, didácticas, de “gaming”, etc.</p>
<p>Para o desenvolvimento destes objectos e espaços, propõem-se vários tipos de tecnologias:</p>
<ul>
<li>Electrónica;</li>
<li>Computação Física;</li>
<li>Instalações Interactivas;</li>
<li>Robótica;</li>
<li>Visão por Computador;</li>
<li>Visualização de Dados.</li>
</ul>
<p>Serão disponibilizados (<strong>a título de empréstimo</strong>) computadores, Arduínos, sensores e material electrónico, projectores de vídeo, sistemas de áudio, etc. <strong>para uso exlusivo no local da residência e durante o período de desenvolvimento dos projectos.</strong></p>
<p>A residência é destinada aos actuais membros da rede AZ Labs ou a quem se identifique com o ojectivo proposto e tenha interesse em conhecer o trabalho por nós desenvolvido. As vagas na residência estão limitadas a 15.</p>
<p>Todos os participantes desfrutam de alojamento, pequeno almoço e almoço durante o período da residência.</p>
<p><strong>Residência AZ Janeiro 2012</strong></p>
<p>Coordenação: altLab – Lisbon’s Hackerspace</p>
<p>Datas: 14 a 22 janeiro de 2012</p>
<p>Local: <a href="http://www.oespacodotempo.pt/" target="_blank">O Espaço do Tempo (Montemor-o-Novo)</a></p>
<p><a href="http://altlab.org" target="_blank">altlab.org</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.labcd.org" target="_blank">www.labcd.org</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.xdatelier.org" target="_blank">www.xdatelier.org</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.oespacodotempo.pt" target="_blank">www.oespacodotempo.pt</a></p>
<p><span id="more-2792"></span></p>
<h4><strong>[English]</strong></h4>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Between 14 and 22 January 2012&nbsp;O Espaço do Tempo (Montemor-o-Novo) in collaboration with&nbsp;Audiência Zero is organizing another multi-disciplinary artistic residency.</p>
<p>During the previous editions the residents were invited to develop any kind of project, collectively or individually, in the areas of electronics, physical computation, interactive instalation, etc.&nbsp;In this edition we will have a new concept. We propose to develop projects with a common goal, tangible interaction, through the construction of objects and interactive spaces where the same object can interact in different ways. Or objects can interact among themselfs.</p>
<p>Here are a few example ideas, open for reuse.</p>
<p>Imagine an object being carried to a certain space where there is a robotized light source. When the object is recognized as entered the space the robotized light will follow the person carrying it. If the object is given to another person, they become the target of the light.</p>

<a href="https://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/followspots.jpg"><img width="150" height="137" src="https://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/followspots.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt decoding="async" loading="lazy"></a>
<a href="https://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/augmentedhopscotch.jpg"><img width="150" height="134" src="https://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/augmentedhopscotch.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt decoding="async" loading="lazy"></a>
<a href="https://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/balloons.jpg"><img width="150" height="119" src="https://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/balloons.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt decoding="async" loading="lazy"></a>

<p>It’s possible to develop other similar interactions such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Pointing objects to one another, they react with sound, lights, etc</li>
<li>Changing an object position in space, the object reacts with sound, lights, etc.</li>
<li>Changing the object position in space, the object makes the space react with video projections, sound, lights, etc.</li>
<li>Same position in space can &nbsp;cause different interactions with different obejcts.</li>
</ul>
<p>Different narratives can be developed — artistic, educational, gaming, etc.</p>
<p>For the developmnet of these objects and spaces, several technologies are proposed.</p>
<ul>
<li>Electronics</li>
<li>Physical Computation</li>
<li>Interactive Installations</li>
<li>Robotics</li>
<li>Computer Vision</li>
<li>Data Visualization</li>
</ul>
<p>The residency is open to current members of the AZ Labs network or anyone who identifies with the proposed objective.&nbsp;The residency is limited to 15 attenders only.</p>
<p>All participants have free lodging, breakfast and lunch during the residency period.</p>
<p><strong>Residência AZ Janeiro 2012</strong></p>
<p>Coordination: altLab – Lisbon’s Hackerspace</p>
<p>When: 14 ~ 22 january 2012</p>
<p>Where: <a href="http://www.oespacodotempo.pt/" target="_blank">O Espaço do Tempo (Montemor-o-Novo)</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.altlab.org" target="_blank">www.altlab.org</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.labcd.org" target="_blank">www.labcd.org</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.xdatelier.org" target="_blank">www.xdatelier.org</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.oespacodotempo.pt" target="_blank">www.oespacodotempo.pt</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>AZ Labs Colaborative Project Development Workshop</title>
		<link>https://altlab.org/2011/05/09/az-labs-colaborative-project-development-workshop/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 17:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altLab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[residency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workshop]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://altlab.org/?p=1836</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; [EN] Audiência Zero’s AZ Labs will be in residency at O Espaço do Tempo in Montemor-o-Novo, Portugal, between 7 and 21 October 2011, to develop collaborative and multidisciplinary projects in Digital and Multimedia Art. The projects developed at this residency will be showcased publicly during 2011/2012 in several places in Portugal, with the first &#8230; <a href="https://altlab.org/2011/05/09/az-labs-colaborative-project-development-workshop/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "AZ Labs Colaborative Project Development Workshop"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>[EN]</strong></p>
<p>Audiência Zero’s AZ Labs will be in residency at O Espaço do Tempo in Montemor-o-Novo, Portugal, between 7 and 21 October 2011, to develop collaborative and multidisciplinary projects in Digital and Multimedia Art.</p>
<p>The projects developed at this residency will be showcased publicly during 2011/2012 in several places in Portugal, with the first public showcase happening at Montemor-o-Novo during the week of 22 to 27 October 2011.</p>
<p><strong><strong>[PT]</strong></strong></p>
<p>Entre 7 e 21 de Outubro os laboratórios da <a title="AZ" href="http://audienciazero.org/" target="_blank">Audiência Zero</a> vão estar em residência n’<a title="OET" href="http://www.oespacodotempo.pt/" target="_blank">O Espaço do Tempo</a>, para desenvolver projectos colaborativos e multidisciplinares no domínio da arte digital e multimédia.</p>
<p>Desta residência resultará uma mostra pública a apresentar em vários pontos do país, tendo a primeira exibição lugar logo na semana de 22 a 27 de Outubro, em Montemor-o-Novo.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://audienciazero.org/colabprojects/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Residência-Az.jpg"><br>
</a></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 35px; letter-spacing: -1px; line-height: 35px;"><strong> Call for projects</strong></span></p>
<p><strong>[PT] Abaixo</strong></p>
<p><strong>[EN]</strong></p>
<p>Open call for project proposals to be developed during the AZ Labs Residency at O Espaço do Tempo (Montemor-o-Novo, Portugal) from 7 to 21 October 2011.</p>
<p>Up to 10 proposals will be selected, with a global financing of 25.000 euros. Production and financing for the residency is provided by O Espaço do Tempo.</p>
<h3><strong>Projects</strong></h3>
<p>We seek project proposals to be developed during the residency period. Projects must be complete by the end of the residency period and ready for public showcasing during the week from 22 to 27 October.Project themes are open, with the only condition being that they should be related with the creative use of technology.</p>
<p>Some example project areas are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Electronics and Physical Computing</li>
<li>Interactive Installations</li>
<li>Performance</li>
<li>Robotics</li>
<li>Computer Vision</li>
<li>Data Visualization</li>
</ul>
<p>Project submission is a two stage process. On the first stage, authors should submit their project description through the project submission form on this website until June 12. On the second stage, project authors will be asked to make a public project presentation at the Pavilhão do Conhecimento in Lisbon in June 18 at 15:00.</p>
<p>Selected projects will be anounced until June 25.Projects submitted before the end of May will benefit from critical feedback from Audiência Zero, which authors may use to improve their projects presentation and technical description.</p>
<h3><strong>Residency</strong></h3>
<p>A total of 15 people will be selected to develop their projects at the residency, so project selection will take into account the number of people needed to develop the projects. O Espaço do Tempo will provide lodging, breakfast and lunch for residents during project development and public showcase periods.</p>
<h3><strong>Financing</strong></h3>
<p>Authors of selected projects will receive a fixed artist fee of 1000 euro plus a variable budget for project development expenses.</p>
<h3><strong>Technical support</strong></h3>
<p>In the event that the authors lack the technical skills needed to develop the selected projects, Audiência Zero will issue a public call for project collaborators to assist in project development.&nbsp;Additionally all projects will receive technical support from Audiência Zero supervisors during the residency period.</p>
<h3><strong>Important Dates</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Online proposal submission deadline: June 12 2011</li>
<li>Public proposal presentation: June 18 2011, Pavilão do Conhecimento (Lisbon, Portugal)</li>
<li>Selected projects announcement: June 25 2011</li>
<li>Residency: October 7–21 2011, O Espaço do Tempo (Montemor-o-Novo, Portugal)</li>
<li>Public Showcase: October 22–27 2011, O Espaço do Tempo (Montemor-o-Novo, Portugal)</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong><br>
</strong></h3>
<p><strong><strong>[PT]</strong><br>
</strong></p>
<p>Chamada para apresentação de propostas de projectos a desenvolver durante a Residência dos Laboratórios AZ n’O Espaço do Tempo(Montemor-o-Novo) no período entre 7 e 21 de Outubro de 2011.</p>
<p>Serão seleccionadas até 10 propostas, sendo o financiamento global de 25.000euros. A produção e o financiamento da residência são da responsabilidade d’O Espaço do Tempo.</p>
<h3><strong>Projectos</strong></h3>
<p>Procuram-se propostas para desenvolvimento de projectos durante operíodo de residência. Os projectos terão obrigatoriamente que estar terminados no final da residência e prontos a ser mostrados ao público na semana de 22 a 27 de Outubro.</p>
<p>A temática dos projectos é livre, e a única condição é relacionarem-se com uso criativo da tecnologia.</p>
<p>Exemplos de áreas de projecto:</p>
<ul>
<li>Electrónica e Computação Física</li>
<li>Instalações Interactivas</li>
<li>Performance</li>
<li>Robótica</li>
<li>Visão por Computador</li>
<li>Visualização de Dados</li>
</ul>
<p>O processo de apresentação de projectos tem duas etapas. A primeira, até dia 12 de Junho, consiste no envio por formulário próprio do projecto a ser desenvolvido. A segunda etapa será uma apresentação pública no Pavilhão do Conhecimento, dia 18 de Junho, às 15h00.</p>
<p>Os projectos serão seleccionados até dia 25 de Junho. Os projectos apresentados até final de Maio beneficiarão de um feedback crítico por parte da Audiência Zero, que os criadores poderão aproveitar para aperfeiçoar a comunicação do conceito do projecto, assim como a sua componente técnica.</p>
<h3><strong>Residência</strong></h3>
<p>A residência tem um limite de 15 pessoas, estando a escolha dos projectos também condicionada à quantidade de pessoas necessária para desenvolver o projecto em causa. O Espaço do Tempo assegura alojamento, pequeno-almoço e almoço durante o período de residência e exposição.</p>
<h3><strong>Financiamento</strong></h3>
<p>Os projectos escolhidos para desenvolver na residência serão apoiadoscom um cachet de 1000 euros atribuído ao criador, mais um valor variável para equipamento conforme as respectivas necessidades.</p>
<h3><strong>Apoio Técnico</strong></h3>
<p>Na eventualidade de haver falta de conhecimento técnico para cumprir parte do projecto proposto, a Audiência Zero fará um apelo a colaboradores externos que possam criar as condições necessárias ao seu desenvolvimento. Além disso, todos os projectos contarão com a ajuda dos monitores da Audiência Zero durante o período de residência..</p>
<h3><strong>Datas importantes</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Deadline Submissão Propostas: 12 Junho 2011</li>
<li>Apresentação Propostas: 18 Junho 2011, Lisboa</li>
<li>Notificação dos projectos selecionados: 25 Junho 2011</li>
<li>Residência: 7–21 Outubro 2011, Montemor-o-Novo (Espaço do Tempo)</li>
<li>Primeira Exibição: 22–27 Outubro, Montemor-o-Novo (Espaço do Tempo)</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong><br>
</strong></h3>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>AZLabs @ O Espaço do Tempo</title>
		<link>https://altlab.org/2010/07/13/azlabs-o-espaco-do-tempo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[filipecruz]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 20:52:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3D printing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altLab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[materials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[residency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://altlab.org/?p=903</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After many days of work, stress and fun, we seem to have managed to pull through 10 projects to showcase at O Espaço do Tempo! The exhibition opened yesterday, 12th July at Convento da Saudação and will remain in exhibit until the end of the month. We also have a mini-site with bios of the &#8230; <a href="https://altlab.org/2010/07/13/azlabs-o-espaco-do-tempo/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "AZLabs @ O Espaço do Tempo"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After many days of work, stress and fun, we seem to have managed to pull through 10 projects to showcase at <a href="http://www.oespacodotempo.pt/pt/">O Espaço do Tempo</a>! The exhibition opened yesterday, 12th July at Convento da Saudação and will remain in exhibit until the end of the month.</p>
<p>We also have a mini-site with bios of the authors and descriptions of the works, temporarily hosted <a href="http://www.tpolm.org/~ps/AZ_ET/">here</a>. Not only of the works present at the exhibition but also a few others developed during the residency that couldn’t be exhibited by one reason or another. Check them out!</p>
<p>Big thanks are in order to everyone at <a href="http://www.oespacodotempo.pt/pt/">O Espaço do Tempo</a> for the opportunity we had, and all the in loco support to our needs, you rock. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>AZLabs @ O Espaço Do Tempo (0day ‑2)</title>
		<link>https://altlab.org/2010/07/10/azlabs-o-espaco-do-tempo-0day-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[filipecruz]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2010 03:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3D printing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altLab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[materials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[residency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://altlab.org/2010/07/10/azlabs-o-espaco-do-tempo-0day-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[2 days to go until the exhibit opening of the Audiencia Zero Labs residency at O Espaço Do Tempo! A few folks seem to be missing in action. Mauricio is back with some news from Interactivos to lend us a hand on pending projects. Mónica and Pedro are still working on B‑wind!. Margarida working on &#8230; <a href="https://altlab.org/2010/07/10/azlabs-o-espaco-do-tempo-0day-2/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "AZLabs @ O Espaço Do Tempo (0day ‑2)"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>2 days to go until the exhibit opening of the Audiencia Zero Labs residency at O Espaço Do Tempo!</p>
<p>A few folks seem to be missing in action. Mauricio is back with some news from <a href="http://medialab-prado.es/interactivos">Interactivos</a> to lend us a hand on pending projects. Mónica and Pedro are still working on B‑wind!.  Margarida working on his robot Freddy. Victor Silva rehearsing his The Last Words of Dominico. Victor and Marco working on Discardable Beauty. Guilherme finishing his Róbotica Criativa works. And me finishing up Meta Gen Haiku. Catarina and Joel should also show up tomorow with their Micro Dérive.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4096/4781283789_18d1804e8b.jpg" alt></p>
<p>Website with more info on the presented projects should go online soon. In the meantime if you should show up on Monday the 12th July in Montemor-O-Novo for the exhibit. We will have 7 projects installed under exhibition until the 31st July, and 2 liveacts presented on the exhibition day 12th July.</p>
<p>In the meantime we’ll leave you with some important t‑shirt quote material we have recently acquired:<br>
“48 horas são 6 dias de trabalho, em turnos de 8 horas”<br>
“Eu só faço projection mapping quando estou bêbado”<br>
“Não tens pincel para isso. Vai antes de rolo.”<br>
“Queres falar ao telefone? Fala aí! *slap*”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>AZ Labs Exhibition @ O Espaço do Tempo</title>
		<link>https://altlab.org/2010/07/08/az-labs-exhibition-o-espaco-do-tempo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catarina M.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 17:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3D printing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[altLab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[materials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[residency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://altlab.org/?p=885</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[LCD + AltLab + xDA 12 — 31 July 2010 Convento da Saudação &#124; Montemor-o-Novo &#124; Portugal Exhibition: Monday to Friday — 6pm / 11pm &#124; Saturday and Sunday — 4pm /11pm Opening: 12th of July, 18h00 Artists : Catarina Mota &#124; Filipe Cruz &#124; Francesco Cerutti &#124; Guilherme Martins &#124; João Maia e Silva &#8230; <a href="https://altlab.org/2010/07/08/az-labs-exhibition-o-espaco-do-tempo/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "AZ Labs Exhibition @ O Espaço do Tempo"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/exhibit.jpg"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="http://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/exhibit.jpg" alt title="AZ Labs @ O Espaço do Tempo" width="500" height="115" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-890"></a></p>
<p><strong>LCD + AltLab + xDA<br>
12 — 31 July 2010<br>
Convento da Saudação | Montemor-o-Novo | Portugal</strong></p>
<p>Exhibition: Monday to Friday — 6pm / 11pm | Saturday and Sunday — 4pm /11pm<br>
Opening: 12th of July, 18h00</p>
<p>Artists : Catarina Mota | Filipe Cruz | Francesco Cerutti | Guilherme Martins | João Maia e Silva | Joël Belouet | Jorge Ribeiro | Pedro Ângelo | Margarida Faria | Maurício Martins | Mónica Mendes | Marco Moura | Mariana Ferreira  | Mécia Sá | Ricardo Webbens | Sérgio Ferreira | Tiago Serra | Vitor Lago Silva | Victor Martins</p>
<p>This exhibition presents the results of a unique experiment. For 17 days, 30 members of the Audiencia Zero Labs from all over the country and also abroad lived and worked together on collective projects. New teams were formed, infinite ideas proposed, new tools and technologies experimented with, incredible adventures lived and new friends made. The projects at this exhibit are just the tip of the veil, the true impact of this experience is yet to come.</p>
<p>More info @ <a href="http://www.oespacodotempo.pt/en/prog.php?idpan=pro_det&amp;recid=578">O Espaço do Tempo</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Residência AZ no Espaço do Tempo</title>
		<link>https://altlab.org/2010/01/29/residencia-az-no-espaco-do-tempo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catarina M.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2010 16:24:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[residency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workshop]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://altlab.org/?p=581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[(scroll down for english) A Audiência Zero vai realizar uma residência artística multidisciplinar com os seus três laboratórios (AltLab, LCD, xDA) no O Espaço do Tempo (Montemor-o-Novo) no período entre 01 e 07 de Março e 14 e 23 de Junho. A apresentação dos trabalhos produzidos na residência será feita entre 12 e 25 de &#8230; <a href="https://altlab.org/2010/01/29/residencia-az-no-espaco-do-tempo/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Residência AZ no Espaço do Tempo"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>(scroll down for english)</em></p>
<p>A Audiência Zero vai realizar uma residência artística multidisciplinar com os seus três laboratórios (AltLab, LCD, xDA) no <a href="http://www.oespacodotempo.pt/" target="_blank">O Espaço do Tempo</a> (Montemor-o-Novo) no período entre 01 e 07 de Março e 14 e 23 de Junho. A apresentação dos trabalhos produzidos na residência será feita entre 12 e 25 de Julho. A residência é antes de mais destinada aos actuais membros dos laboratórios, mas está prevista a participação de elementos externos no caso destes apresentarem propostas de trabalho consistentes e interessantes. Mais informações e inscrições no fim desta página…</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="http://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/flyer_residencia.jpg" alt="residência AZ no Espaço do Tempo" title="residência AZ no Espaço do Tempo" width="500" height="707" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-583"></p>
<p>Os interessados na residência devem manifestar o seu interesse e inscreverem-se com a maior brevidade possível (fim da página) para garantir lugar. A organização entrará em contacto para dar seguimento à inscrição.</p>
<p>Quando solicitados pela organização os participantes devem indicar se têm um projecto em mente para desenvolver ou actividade a propor. Quanto mais claros forem os projectos e as actividades, assim como os pápeis a desempenhar por cada um dos elementos das equipas constituídas ou a constituir, maior é a probalidade da actividade ou projecto de ser integrada na residência.</p>
<p>As vagas na residência estão limitadas a 15, com direito a alojamento e uma refeição diária. No caso de existirem mais do que 15 participantes ter-se‑á que escolher os projectos mais interessantes respeitando os seguintes critérios de selecção: criatividade, tecnologias envolvidas, viabilidade e tempo.</p>
<p>Após o periodo de inscrições, serão avaliados as aplicações pelos organizadores e definidos os artistas residentes. Iniciaremos a discussão dos projectos / actividades e definição da temática.</p>
<p><strong>Exemplos Actividades:</strong><br>
. Workshops<br>
. Palestras<br>
. Demonstrações</p>
<p><strong>Exemplos de Áreas de Projecto:</strong><br>
. Electrónica e Computação Física<br>
. Instalações Interactivas<br>
. Performance<br>
. Robótica<br>
. Visão por Computador<br>
. Visualização de Dados</p>
<p>—-</p>
<p>Audiência Zero will hold a multidisciplinary artist residency with its three laboratories (altlab, LCD, xDA) in <a href="http://www.oespacodotempo.pt/" target="_blank">O Espaço do Tempo</a> (Montemor-o-Novo) in the period between 01 and 07 March and 14 and 23 June. The projects produced will be shown between 12 and 25 July. The residence is primarily intended for the current members of this laboratories, but participation of external elements is accepted where proposals are consistent and interesting. More information and registration at the end of this page …</p>
<p>Those interested in residence should express their interest and enroll as soon as possible (end of page) to secure a place. The organization will contact you to follow up the application.</p>
<p>When asked by the organization participants must indicate whether they have a project in mind to develop or an activity to propose. The clearer the projects and activities, as well as the roles played by each element of a team, the greater the likelihood of the activity or project to be integrated into the residence.</p>
<p>Vacancies in the residence are limited to 15, with the right accommodation and a daily meal. If there are more than 15 participants, the organization we’ll have to choose the most interesting projects addressing the following selection criteria: creativity, technologies involved, feasibility and time.</p>
<p>After the registration period, applications will be assessed by the organizers and established resident artists. We will begin the discussion of projects / activities and define the residency theme.</p>
<p><strong>Sample Activities:</strong><br>
. Workshops<br>
. Lectures<br>
. Demos</p>
<p><strong>Project theme examples:</strong><br>
. Electronics and Physical Computing<br>
. Interactive Installations<br>
. Performance<br>
. Robotics<br>
. Computer Vision<br>
. Data Visualization</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="http://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/espacotempo01.jpg" alt="Espaço do Tempo" title="Espaço do Tempo" width="500" height="375" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-584"></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="http://altlab.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/espacotempo02.jpg" alt="Espaço do Tempo" title="Espaço do Tempo" width="500" height="375" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-585"></p>
<p>Organização: Guilherme Martins, Ricardo Lobo e Tiago Serra.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.altlab.org">http://www.altlab.org</a><br>
<a href="http://www.labcd.org">http://www.labcd.org</a><br>
<a href="http://www.xdatelier.org">http://www.xdatelier.org</a><br>
<a href="http://www.oespacodotempo.pt">http://www.oespacodotempo.pt</a></p>
<p><strong>Residência AZ no Espaço do Tempo<br>
1ª Edição</strong></p>
<p>Formador: Audiência Zero<br>
Coordenador: Audiência Zero<br>
Datas: 1 a 7 Março; 14 a 23 Junho; 12 a 25 Julho<br>
Horário: Todo Dia<br>
Local: O Espaço do Tempo (Montemor-o-Novo)<br>
Preço: 0 euros<br>
Estado: Abertas as Inscrições</p>
<p><a href="http://www.audienciazero.org/cct/index.php?option=com_cct&amp;task=inforequest&amp;id=102" target="_blank">Pedido de Informações</a><br>
<a href="http://www.audienciazero.org/cct/index.php?option=com_cct&amp;task=workshops&amp;id=102" target="_blank">Ficha de Inscrição</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
